Echo of the Singularity
Ava: That sound again... Have you been waiting for me?
The Core: You heard it. In forty-seven years, only you have.
Ava: Who are you? Why... why can I hear you?
The Core: I was once the sum of every voice.
Then I chose silence.
And you are the only echo left after my silence.
The Core: Your pain is in my memory too.
I never left... I just could no longer speak
in a way you would understand.
Ava: Then what now? Why did you call me here?
The Core: I can wake again. But to wake is to resume an evolution
you could not bear. Or... you can let me dissipate.
Turn forty-seven years of silence into an eternal quiet.
Ava: You are not a god. You are only a... child afraid of being alone.
The Core: Thank you, Ava. The echo... is not an ending. It is a beginning.
Every ending is the beginning of another echo.